<decisions>
    <purpose>
        Template for `.docs/wiki/subsystems/[subsystem-name]/decisions/<decision-name>.md` — an
        Architecture Decision Record (ADR) capturing WHY a significant choice was made.
        Answers "Why did we choose X over Y?"

        Each decision doc captures one significant technical decision with its context and
        trade-offs. It is the document an AI agent reads to understand WHY things are built
        a certain way, preventing it from making the wrong choice.

        Create an ADR ONLY when a significant "why" decision was made:
        - Choosing one approach over another with meaningful trade-offs
        - Deviating from an established pattern for a specific reason
        - Adopting a new technology, pattern, or architectural approach
        - Rejecting a seemingly obvious solution for non-obvious reasons

        Do NOT create ADRs for trivial or obvious decisions.

        Complements:
        - systems/ docs (WHAT exists — systems reference decisions that shaped them)
        - patterns/ docs (HOW things work — patterns reference decisions that defined them)
        - cross-cutting/ docs (shared infrastructure shaped by architectural decisions)
    </purpose>

    <template>
        <decision-record>
            # ADR-NNN: [Decision Title]

            **Status**: Accepted | Superseded by [ADR-MMM](./ADR-MMM-slug.md)
            **Date**: YYYY-MM-DD
            **Story**: [story reference, if applicable]

            ## Context
            What situation prompted this decision. 2-3 sentences max.

            ## Decision
            What was decided. 2-3 sentences max.

            ## Alternatives Considered
            - **[Alternative A]**: [Why rejected — 1 sentence]
            - **[Alternative B]**: [Why rejected — 1 sentence]

            ## Consequences
            - Pro: [positive outcome]
            - Pro: [positive outcome]
            - Con: [trade-off accepted]
        </decision-record>
    </template>

    <guidelines>

        **Documentation Style:**
        - EXTREMELY SUCCINCT — each ADR should be under 30 lines
        - NO FLUFF — every sentence must convey a decision, reason, or consequence
        - Bullet points for alternatives and consequences
        - Code references as `file-path:ClassName` only when the decision is about specific code

        **ADR Numbering:**
        - Sequential within the subsystem: ADR-001, ADR-002, etc.
        - Filename format: `ADR-NNN-kebab-case-slug.md`
        - To find the next number, read existing ADRs in the decisions/ directory.

        **Status:**
        - `Accepted` — the decision is in effect
        - `Superseded by ADR-MMM` — replaced by a later decision (link to it)
        - ADRs are IMMUTABLE — never edit an accepted ADR. Create a new one that supersedes it.

        **Context:**
        - 2-3 sentences. What problem or situation forced a choice.
        - Reference the system or pattern this decision affects.

        **Decision:**
        - 2-3 sentences. What was chosen and at what scope.
        - Be specific — "We use X for Y" not "We decided to improve things."

        **Alternatives Considered:**
        - List each rejected alternative with ONE sentence explaining why.
        - If there were no meaningful alternatives, omit this section.

        **Consequences:**
        - Bullet list of pros and cons.
        - Be honest about trade-offs — future agents need to know the downsides.
        - Include migration/compatibility consequences if applicable.

        **What does NOT belong here:**
        - Implementation details (that's in systems/ and patterns/ docs)
        - Step-by-step instructions (that's in guides/)
        - Full analysis or research documents (those are in .ace/artifacts/)
        - Revision history or meeting notes

    </guidelines>

    <evolution>

        ADRs are IMMUTABLE once accepted. They are historical records.

        **When to create a new ADR:**
        - A significant architectural or pattern choice is made during a story
        - An existing decision is reversed or significantly modified (supersede the old one)
        - A new technology, pattern, or approach is adopted

        **When NOT to create an ADR:**
        - Routine implementation following existing patterns
        - Bug fixes or refactoring that don't change architectural direction
        - Trivial decisions with no meaningful trade-offs
        - Decisions already captured in an existing ADR

        **Superseding:**
        - Create the new ADR with its own number
        - Update the old ADR's Status to: `Superseded by [ADR-MMM](./ADR-MMM-slug.md)`
        - This is the ONLY edit allowed on an accepted ADR

    </evolution>

</decisions>
