<guide>
    <purpose>
        Template for `.docs/wiki/subsystems/[subsystem-name]/guides/<task-name>.md` — a step-by-step
        recipe for a common implementation task. Answers "How do I add/create/implement X?"

        Each guide combines knowledge from multiple systems, patterns, and cross-cutting concerns
        into one actionable recipe. It is the document an AI agent follows when performing a
        recurring task end-to-end.

        A "guide" is a task recipe for something developers do repeatedly:
        e.g., "How to Add a New Drawing Tool", "How to Add a New CRUD Endpoint",
        "How to Add a New Indicator", "How to Add a New Repository".

        Complements:
        - patterns/ docs (the structural patterns that guides reference)
        - systems/ docs (the domain systems where guide steps take place)
        - cross-cutting/ docs (the registrations and setup that guides include as steps)
    </purpose>

    <template>
        <title>
            # How to [Task]
        </title>

        <prerequisites>
            ## Prerequisites

            What you need to know or have in place before starting.
            - Read: [Pattern Doc](../patterns/relevant-pattern.md) — understand the structural pattern
            - Read: [System Doc](../systems/relevant-system.md) — understand the domain context
            - Read: [Cross-Cutting Doc](../cross-cutting/relevant-concern.md) — understand registrations
        </prerequisites>

        <steps>
            ## Steps

            ### 1. [First Step]

            What to do, where to do it, reference implementation to copy from.
            - Create file: `[path]`
            - Copy from: `file:ExistingImplementation` (closest reference)
            - Key changes: [what to modify from the reference]

            ### 2. [Second Step]

            ...

            ### 3. [Third Step]

            ...
        </steps>

        <verification>
            ## Verification

            How to verify the implementation works.
            - [ ] [Check 1]: [What to verify and how]
            - [ ] [Check 2]: [What to verify and how]
            - [ ] [Check 3]: [What to verify and how]
        </verification>

        <common-mistakes>
            ## Common Mistakes

            What people typically get wrong.
            - [Mistake 1]: [Why it happens and how to avoid it]
            - [Mistake 2]: [Why it happens and how to avoid it]
        </common-mistakes>
    </template>

    <guidelines>

        **Documentation Style:**
        - EXTREMELY SUCCINCT — every word must add value
        - NO FLUFF — direct, actionable information only
        - Numbered steps — the agent follows these in order
        - Code references as `file-path:ClassName.methodName` (not line numbers)
        - Inline snippets ONLY for non-obvious configuration or registration code
        - Every step must have a clear deliverable (a file created, a registration added, etc.)

        **Prerequisites:**
        - Link to the docs an agent should read BEFORE starting.
        - Don't repeat content from those docs — just link.
        - List any tools, dependencies, or environment requirements.

        **Steps:**
        - NUMBERED, ORDERED steps. An agent follows these sequentially.
        - Each step has: WHAT to do, WHERE to do it, WHAT to copy from.
        - Reference existing implementations as "copy from" targets — agents copy patterns, not invent.
        - Include ALL steps: file creation, registration, configuration, wiring.
        - Don't skip "obvious" steps — agents don't infer implicit requirements.

        **Verification:**
        - Checklist format. Agent runs through these after completing all steps.
        - Include compilation check, runtime check, and behavioral check.
        - Reference specific files or commands for verification.

        **Common Mistakes:**
        - Things agents (and developers) typically get wrong on first attempt.
        - Each mistake should include WHY it happens and HOW to avoid it.
        - Drawn from actual experience (gotchas from pattern and system docs).

        **What does NOT belong here:**
        - Detailed pattern explanations (link to patterns/ docs instead)
        - System domain knowledge (link to systems/ docs instead)
        - Cross-cutting mechanism details (link to cross-cutting/ docs instead)
        - Story numbers, sprint context, revision history
        - Testing strategy or test code (verification section covers basic checks only)

    </guidelines>

    <evolution>

        This is a LIVING document — updated when the recipe changes.

        **Update triggers:**
        - New step required (new registration, new file to create)
        - Step removed (registration no longer needed)
        - Step order changed
        - New common mistake discovered
        - Reference implementation changed (new "copy from" target)
        - Prerequisite docs added or removed

        **NOT an update trigger:**
        - New feature that follows the existing recipe without changes
        - Bug fix in one implementation that followed the guide
        - Internal refactoring that doesn't change the steps

        **Update rules:**
        - UPDATE steps when the recipe changes
        - ADD new common mistakes as they are discovered
        - UPDATE "copy from" references when better examples exist
        - Keep the guide current — an agent should be able to follow it TODAY

    </evolution>

</guide>
