<pattern>
    <purpose>
        Template for `.docs/wiki/subsystems/[subsystem-name]/patterns/<pattern-name>.md` — a reusable
        implementation pattern within a codebase subsystem. Answers "HOW do I implement something
        that follows this pattern?"

        Each pattern doc describes a structural template that appears across multiple implementations.
        It is the document an AI agent reads to ensure new code follows established conventions.

        A "pattern" is a recurring structural approach used by 2+ implementations:
        e.g., Template Method (Path base class with 5 factory methods), Repository Pattern,
        Mapper Pattern, Factory/Registry, CQRS Command/Query handlers.

        Complements:
        - systems/ docs (WHAT exists — the domain subsystems that USE these patterns)
        - guides/ docs (step-by-step recipes that COMBINE multiple patterns into a task)
        - cross-cutting/ docs (shared infrastructure that patterns depend on)
    </purpose>

    <template>
        <the-pattern>
            # [Pattern Name]

            ## The Pattern
            What it is, when to use it. One paragraph max.
        </the-pattern>

        <structure>
            ## Structure

            Class/interface diagram showing the pattern's structure.

            ```mermaid
            classDiagram
                class IContract {
                    &lt;&lt;interface&gt;&gt;
                    +method() ReturnType
                }
                class AbstractBase {
                    &lt;&lt;abstract&gt;&gt;
                    +templateMethod()
                    #factoryMethod()* ReturnType
                }
                IContract &lt;|.. AbstractBase
                AbstractBase &lt;|-- ConcreteA
                AbstractBase &lt;|-- ConcreteB
            ```
        </structure>

        <how-it-works>
            ## How It Works

            Step-by-step of the pattern mechanics. Reference actual code locations.

            1. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
            2. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
            3. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
        </how-it-works>

        <how-to-apply>
            ## How to Apply

            When implementing something new that uses this pattern:

            1. [First step] (reference: `file:ClassName.method`)
            2. [Second step]
            3. [Third step]
            ...
        </how-to-apply>

        <current-implementations>
            ## Current Implementations

            Where this pattern is currently used:
            - `TrendLine` at `src/infrastructure/primitives/trend-line/TrendLine.ts`
            - `ParallelChannel` at `src/infrastructure/primitives/parallel-channel/ParallelChannel.ts`
            - ...
        </current-implementations>

        <gotchas>
            ## Gotchas

            Things that commonly go wrong or are easy to forget when applying this pattern.
            - [Common mistake 1]
            - [Common mistake 2]
        </gotchas>
    </template>

    <guidelines>

        **Documentation Style:**
        - EXTREMELY SUCCINCT — every word must add value
        - NO FLUFF — direct, actionable information only
        - Bullet points over paragraphs
        - Code references as `file-path:ClassName.methodName` (not line numbers)
        - Inline snippets ONLY for interface contracts and pattern structure definitions
        - **ALL visual representations of architecture, dependencies, flows, or relationships MUST be ```mermaid fenced code blocks (use `classDiagram` for structure). NO ASCII arrows (->), NO dependency trees, NO PlantUML. Only mermaid. The ONLY ASCII exception is file trees.**

        **The Pattern:**
        - ONE paragraph. Name the GoF/industry pattern if applicable, then explain how it
          manifests in THIS codebase. Not a textbook definition — the codebase-specific version.

        **Structure:**
        - Mermaid classDiagram showing the abstract/interface hierarchy.
        - Show the pattern skeleton only — not every concrete implementation.
        - Include key method signatures that define the contract.

        **How It Works:**
        - Numbered steps tracing the pattern's execution flow.
        - Every step references actual code with `file:ClassName.method`.
        - Focus on the mechanics an agent needs to understand to add a new implementation.

        **How to Apply:**
        - The MOST ACTIONABLE section. An agent follows these steps to create a new instance.
        - Reference existing implementations as "copy from" targets.
        - Include which files to create, which registrations to add, which factories to update.

        **Current Implementations:**
        - Complete list of all known implementations with file paths.
        - Agent uses this as a reference gallery — "pick the closest one and copy its structure."
        - Update when new implementations are added.

        **Gotchas:**
        - Timing issues, naming conventions, registration requirements, common mistakes.
        - Anything an agent would get wrong on first attempt without being told.

        **What does NOT belong here:**
        - System-specific domain logic (that's in systems/ docs)
        - Step-by-step task recipes that combine multiple patterns (that's in guides/)
        - Cross-cutting infrastructure details (that's in cross-cutting/)
        - Story numbers, sprint context, revision history
        - Testing instructions, performance benchmarks

    </guidelines>

    <evolution>

        This is a LIVING document — updated when the pattern itself evolves.

        **Update triggers:**
        - New implementation added (update Current Implementations list)
        - Pattern structure changed (new factory method, new interface method)
        - How to Apply steps changed (new registration requirement, new file to create)
        - New gotcha discovered during implementation

        **NOT an update trigger:**
        - New feature that follows the existing pattern without changing it
        - Bug fix in one implementation
        - Internal refactoring that doesn't change the pattern contract

        **Update rules:**
        - ADD new implementations to the list
        - UPDATE How to Apply if the recipe changed
        - ADD new gotchas as they are discovered
        - Do NOT remove historical gotchas unless they are no longer relevant

    </evolution>

</pattern>
