<system-cross-cutting>
    <purpose>
        Template for `.docs/wiki/subsystems/[subsystem-name]/cross-cutting/<concern-name>.md` — a
        concern that spans multiple systems within a codebase subsystem. Answers "How does this
        shared infrastructure/concern work, and how do I plug into it?"

        Each cross-cutting doc describes shared infrastructure or mechanisms that multiple domain
        systems depend on. It is the document an AI agent reads to understand how to register,
        configure, or interact with shared concerns.

        Examples of cross-cutting concerns:
        - Dependency injection and container registration
        - Factory/registry registration patterns
        - Event systems, invalidation, pub/sub
        - Serialization/deserialization
        - Error handling and logging infrastructure
        - Authentication/authorization middleware
        - Cache/invalidation infrastructure
        - Shared abstract base classes

        Complements:
        - systems/ docs (domain systems that USE these cross-cutting concerns)
        - patterns/ docs (reusable structural patterns, not shared infrastructure)
        - guides/ docs (task recipes that reference cross-cutting setup steps)
    </purpose>

    <template>
        <overview>
            # [Cross-Cutting Concern]

            ## Overview
            What this concern addresses, why it exists. One paragraph.
        </overview>

        <how-it-works>
            ## How It Works

            The pattern/mechanism used. Reference actual code locations.

            1. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
            2. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
            3. **Step**: Description at `file:ClassName.method`
        </how-it-works>

        <registration-and-setup>
            ## Registration / Setup

            Where and how components register with this concern.
            - **Container**: `file:container.ts:registerServices`
            - **Factory**: `file:DrawingFactory.ts:DrawingFactory`
            - **Registry**: `file:DrawingRegistry.ts:DrawingRegistry`
        </registration-and-setup>

        <usage>
            ## Usage

            How other systems interact with this concern.

            ```typescript
            // Usage pattern (inline only if non-obvious)
            ```
        </usage>

        <current-registrations>
            ## Current Registrations / Implementations

            What is currently registered/using this concern:
            - `TrendLine` registered at `file:container.ts:registerDrawings`
            - `ParallelChannel` registered at `file:container.ts:registerDrawings`
            - ...
        </current-registrations>

        <integration-points>
            ## Integration Points

            Where this concern connects to other systems.
            - [System A](../systems/system-a.md) — uses this for [purpose]
            - [System B](../systems/system-b.md) — uses this for [purpose]
        </integration-points>

        <gotchas>
            ## Gotchas

            Common mistakes when working with this concern.
            - [Common mistake 1]
            - [Common mistake 2]
        </gotchas>

        <tech-debt>
            ## Tech Debt

            Known quality issues in this cross-cutting concern discovered during story code reviews.
            Items are added by the wiki mapper and removed when fixed by a future story.
            Include ONLY if this concern has known tech debt items. Omit section entirely if clean.

            ### [Short descriptive title of the issue]
            - **Severity:** high | medium | low
            - **File:** `[file-path:SymbolName]`
            - **Description:** What the issue is, why it matters, and what could go wrong
              if left unfixed. For cross-cutting concerns, note which dependent systems are affected.
            - **Discovered during:** [story-id] — [story title]

            ### [Another issue]
            - **Severity:** ...
            - **File:** ...
            - **Description:** ...
            - **Discovered during:** ...
        </tech-debt>
    </template>

    <guidelines>

        **Documentation Style:**
        - EXTREMELY SUCCINCT — every word must add value
        - NO FLUFF — direct, actionable information only
        - Bullet points over paragraphs
        - Code references as `file-path:ClassName.methodName` (not line numbers)
        - Inline snippets ONLY for usage patterns and registration examples
        - **ALL visual representations of architecture, dependencies, flows, or relationships MUST be ```mermaid fenced code blocks. NO ASCII arrows (->), NO dependency trees, NO PlantUML. Only mermaid. The ONLY ASCII exception is file trees.**

        **Overview:**
        - ONE paragraph. What the concern does and why it exists.
        - Focus on what an agent needs to know to interact with this concern.

        **How It Works:**
        - Numbered steps explaining the mechanism.
        - Reference actual code locations — not theoretical descriptions.
        - If the mechanism has a flow (event dispatching, DI resolution), show a mermaid sequence diagram.

        **Registration / Setup:**
        - The MOST CRITICAL section for AI agents. They need to know WHERE to register new things.
        - List every registration point with exact file paths.
        - Show the registration pattern (inline code only if non-obvious).

        **Usage:**
        - How consuming code interacts with this concern.
        - Inline code snippet ONLY if the usage pattern is non-obvious.
        - If usage is straightforward (e.g., inject via constructor), a one-liner suffices.

        **Current Registrations / Implementations:**
        - Complete list of everything currently registered/using this concern.
        - Agent uses this to verify its new registration is consistent with existing ones.
        - Update when new registrations are added.

        **Integration Points:**
        - Cross-reference with markdown links to system docs that depend on this concern.
        - Helps agents understand the blast radius of changes to this concern.

        **Gotchas:**
        - Registration order dependencies, naming conventions, initialization timing.
        - Anything that silently fails if done wrong.

        **Tech Debt:**
        - One `###` subsection per known issue — NOT a table. Each issue needs enough context
          for an agent to understand the problem without reading the code.
        - For cross-cutting concerns, always note which dependent systems are affected.
        - Severity: `high` (security, data loss, production instability), `medium` (quality,
          maintainability), `low` (cosmetic, minor inefficiency).
        - Always link to the discovering story for traceability.
        - REMOVE items when fixed by a future story.
        - Omit the entire section if no tech debt exists in this concern.

        **What does NOT belong here:**
        - Domain-specific logic (that's in systems/ docs)
        - Reusable structural patterns (that's in patterns/ docs)
        - Step-by-step task recipes (that's in guides/ docs)
        - Story numbers, sprint context, revision history
        - Testing instructions, performance benchmarks

    </guidelines>

    <evolution>

        This is a LIVING document — updated when the cross-cutting concern changes.

        **Update triggers:**
        - New registration added (update Current Registrations list)
        - Registration mechanism changed (new file, new pattern)
        - New integration point discovered
        - New gotcha discovered
        - Setup/initialization process changed
        - Tech debt discovered or resolved in this concern's files

        **NOT an update trigger:**
        - New feature that registers with existing mechanism without changing it
        - Bug fix in one registered component
        - Internal refactoring of the mechanism that doesn't change the external API

        **Update rules:**
        - ADD new registrations to the list
        - UPDATE Registration / Setup if the process changed
        - ADD new gotchas as they are discovered
        - REMOVE registrations for deleted components

    </evolution>

</system-cross-cutting>
