<walkthrough>
    <purpose>
        Template for `.docs/wiki/subsystems/[subsystem-name]/walkthroughs/<flow-name>.md` — a deep,
        tutorial-style explanation of a complex end-to-end flow. Answers "Walk me through EXACTLY
        what happens when X."

        Each walkthrough traces a single flow from entry point to exit point, showing ACTUAL code
        from the codebase at every step, explaining what each piece does and WHY, and calling out
        framework/library concepts with info boxes when external tools are involved.

        Written for humans (especially new developers and interns) who need to UNDERSTAND a flow
        before they can work with it. Unlike system docs (terse references for AI agents),
        walkthroughs prioritize completeness of information — but deliver it in minimal words.

        A "walkthrough" is a traced execution flow through multiple classes and layers:
        e.g., "Message arrives via SignalR until it reaches the LLM", "LLM calls a tool until
        the drawing appears on the chart", "User places an order until it's confirmed".

        Create a walkthrough when:
        - A flow spans 3+ classes across multiple architectural layers
        - External frameworks/libraries are involved that need explanation (MAF, SignalR, EF Core)
        - A system doc would need paragraphs of explanation with code snippets (that's a walkthrough, not a system doc)
        - An intern reading the code alone would not understand what's happening without guidance

        **Emphasis Frameworks:**
        Walkthroughs can specify one or more "emphasis frameworks" — external frameworks,
        libraries, APIs, or SDKs that deserve deep explanation throughout the walkthrough.
        When an emphasis framework is specified:
        - EVERY step where the flow touches that framework MUST have a framework info box
        - The info box explains the specific framework concept used in that step
        - ALL code from ALL steps that interact with the emphasis framework is shown and explained
        - The agent researches the framework (via WebSearch/context7 or provided docs) if needed
        - The Framework Concepts Reference table at the end is MANDATORY

        Examples of emphasis frameworks: SignalR, EF Core, MAF (Microsoft Agent Framework),
        React Query, gRPC, MediatR, AutoMapper. Can be specified by name (agent researches)
        or with documentation paths/URLs (agent reads provided docs).

        Complements:
        - systems/ docs (terse WHAT reference — walkthroughs explain the HOW in depth)
        - patterns/ docs (reusable structural patterns — walkthroughs trace specific flows through them)
        - guides/ docs (procedural recipes for DOING — walkthroughs explain for UNDERSTANDING)
        - cross-cutting/ docs (shared infrastructure — walkthroughs show how flows pass through them)
    </purpose>

    <template>
        <title>
            # [Flow Name]

            One line: what this flow does and when it triggers.
        </title>

        <file-map>
            ## Files Involved

            Every file this flow touches, in execution order.

            ```
            src/[layer]/[area]/
            |-- FileA.cs                    # Entry point
            |-- FileB.cs                    # Orchestrates flow
            |-- FileC.cs                    # Core logic
            `-- FileD.cs                    # Sends result
            ```
        </file-map>

        <flow-diagram>
            ## Flow Overview

            ```mermaid
            sequenceDiagram
                participant A as ComponentA
                participant B as ComponentB
                participant C as ComponentC
                participant D as ExternalSystem

                A->>B: step description
                B->>C: step description
                C->>D: step description
                D-->>C: response
                C-->>B: result
                B-->>A: result
            ```

            Participants = real classes/components. Arrows = real method calls.
            Steps below explain each arrow.
        </flow-diagram>

        <steps>
            ## Step-by-Step

            ### Step 1: [What happens]

            **File:** `path/to/File.cs:ClassName.MethodName`

            [1-2 sentences: what this step does and WHY. No filler.]

            ```csharp
            // Actual code from the codebase
            public async Task MethodName(string param1, string param2)
            {
                var result = await _dependency.DoSomething(param1);
            }
            ```

            `_dependency` — injected via constructor, does X.
            `param1` — the Y received from Z.
            [Only explain what's non-obvious. Skip what the code already says clearly.]

            ---

            ### Step 2: [What happens]

            **File:** `path/to/AnotherFile.cs:ClassName.MethodName`

            [What and why — terse.]

            ```csharp
            // Actual code...
            ```

            > **[Framework]: [Concept]**
            >
            > [Succinct explanation of the framework concept. What it is, what it does for us.
            > No history, no alternatives, no "in general" — just what the reader needs to
            > understand THIS code.]
            >
            > *Source: [link to official docs]*

            ---

            ### Step 3: [What happens]

            ...continue for every step in the flow...
        </steps>

        <framework-concepts>
            ## Framework Concepts Reference

            Consolidated lookup for framework concepts explained inline above.

            | Concept | Framework | What It Does | First Appearance |
            |---------|-----------|-------------|------------------|
            | `AIFunctionFactory.Create()` | MS Agent Framework | C# method -> LLM tool | [Step N](#step-n) |
            | `ChatClientAgent` | MS Agent Framework | Wraps IChatClient with auto tool loop | [Step M](#step-m) |

            Include ONLY if external frameworks/libraries are involved.
        </framework-concepts>

        <related-docs>
            ## Related Documentation

            - [System Doc](../systems/relevant-system.md) — terse reference
            - [Guide](../guides/relevant-guide.md) — recipe for adding to this flow
            - [Official Docs](../framework-docs/relevant-page.md) — framework docs
        </related-docs>
    </template>

    <guidelines>

        ### Density Over Prose
        - **EXTREMELY SUCCINCT** — every word must add value. If a word does not add value, remove it.
        - **NO FLUFF** — no introductions, no summaries of what the section will contain, no transitions
        - Bullet points over paragraphs. Tables over bullet points when comparing.
        - If you can say it in 3 words, don't use 10. Then try to say it in 2.
        - **BUT: ALL needed information MUST be present.** Succinctness means cutting WORDS, not cutting INFORMATION. Every concept, every parameter, every non-obvious behavior must be explained — just in fewer words.

        ### Complete but Dense Explanations
        - Explain the WHY, not just the WHAT — "X because Y" not "X happens"
        - After each code snippet: explain ONLY what's non-obvious. If the code says `price > 0`, don't write "checks that price is positive" — the code already says that. DO explain hidden behaviors, framework magic, non-obvious field origins.
        - Use inline code references for fields/params: `` `_connectionId` — captured from `Context.ConnectionId` in AgentHub ``
        - One-line explanations preferred. Multi-line only when genuinely complex.

        ### Code Snippets (MANDATORY per step)
        - ALWAYS from the actual codebase — verified by reading the file
        - NEVER pseudocode, NEVER summaries, NEVER fabricated
        - Use correct language tag: ```csharp, ```typescript, ```json
        - **FOCUSED**: show ONLY the lines relevant to what the step is explaining. If a method has 50 lines but this step is about lines 10-15, show lines 10-15 with a `// ... (validation above)` or `// ... (setup omitted)` comment for context. The snippet serves the step's explanation, not the other way around.
        - Short methods (under 20 lines) where the ENTIRE method is relevant: show entirely
        - Long methods: show the relevant portion only. Use `// ...` comments to indicate omitted sections above/below.

        ### Flow Diagram (MANDATORY)
        - Every walkthrough MUST start with a mermaid sequenceDiagram
        - Participants = real classes/components, not abstract concepts
        - Arrows = real method calls, labeled with method name
        - The diagram is the map; the steps are the guided tour

        ### Framework Info Boxes (when applicable)
        - Use markdown blockquotes (`>`) with `> **[Framework]: [Concept]**` header
        - Explain as if the reader has NEVER used this framework — but in minimal words
        - Place IMMEDIATELY after the first code snippet that uses the concept
        - Each concept explained ONCE — do not repeat
        - Link to official docs with `*Source: [link]*`
        - Keep it dense: what it is, what it does for us, done. No history, no alternatives.

        ### Emphasis Frameworks (when specified)
        - When emphasis-frameworks are specified, framework info boxes become MANDATORY
          for EVERY step that touches the emphasis framework — not just the first occurrence
        - ALL code that interacts with the emphasis framework must be shown in full
        - The Framework Concepts Reference table is MANDATORY (not optional)
        - If the agent does not know the framework: use WebSearch or context7 MCP to research it
        - If framework docs are provided (file paths or URLs): read them BEFORE writing any steps

        ### Minimum Length
        - At least 300 lines — length comes from code snippets and completeness, not from prose
        - Complex flows (3+ frameworks, 10+ classes): 500-1000 lines
        - Under 200 lines = not enough information, add more steps/explanations

        ### Section Inclusion
        - Title, File Map, Flow Diagram, Step-by-Step: ALWAYS required
        - Framework Concepts Reference: MANDATORY if emphasis-frameworks specified; otherwise ONLY if external frameworks involved
        - Related Documentation: ALWAYS required

        ### What Does NOT Belong Here
        - Terse bullet-point references (that's systems/)
        - Structural pattern descriptions (that's patterns/)
        - Procedural "how to add X" recipes (that's guides/)
        - Architecture decision rationale (that's decisions/)
        - Story numbers, sprint context, revision history
        - Testing instructions or test code
        - Frontend code in a backend walkthrough (or vice versa) — scope to ONE side
        - Speculation about future changes — document what IS, not what might be
        - Filler phrases: "Let's look at", "Now we'll examine", "As mentioned above", "It's worth noting"

    </guidelines>

    <evolution>

        This is a LIVING document — updated when the flow it describes changes.

        **Update triggers:**
        - New step added to the flow
        - Step removed from the flow
        - Step logic changed significantly
        - Framework/library upgraded, APIs changed
        - Code snippets no longer match codebase
        - New framework concept introduced

        **NOT an update trigger:**
        - Bug fixes that don't change flow structure
        - Internal refactoring within a single step
        - New feature using a DIFFERENT flow (create a new walkthrough)
        - Style/formatting changes to the code

        **Update rules:**
        - UPDATE code snippets to match current codebase — stale snippets are worse than no docs
        - ADD new steps when the flow gains a stage
        - REMOVE steps that no longer exist
        - UPDATE framework info boxes when APIs change
        - UPDATE mermaid diagram to reflect current flow
        - Document must always reflect CURRENT code state, not history

    </evolution>

</walkthrough>
